AVIRAL SRIVASTAVA

Phone: +91-7073865049

Email: srivastavaaviral1@gmail.com

LinkedIn: aviral-srivastava Github: iamaaviral Website: iamaaviral.com

PROFILE

Aviral is a front-end software developer with experience of building web and mobile applications using a variety of tools and has exposure to the entire gamut of software development lifecycle working on areas ranging all the way from data modeling to UI design and release management. He has experience working in the fast paced, highly competitive startup culture. He is appreciated for his individual contributions to the product, as well as handling the responsibility of coordinating the team to get work done. His mission is to design solutions that improve the quality of life of millions of people.

SKILLS

- Languages Javascript, Typescript, Html5, CSS3
- Frontend Libraries and Frameworks- React, React Native, React- query, Jquery, Bootstrap
- Testing utilities- Jest, Enzyme
- version-control system- Git, Apache Subversion(svn)
- UI Designing tools- Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jun 2022 – Present
Senior Software Engineer
Pepper content
Remote

- Pepper content is an AI-powered content marketing platform with an expert led talent marketplace.
- Worked extensively on the in-house product as a front-end dev. Work involves requirements analysis, data modeling, technology exploration and selection, software design, construction, and testing, and release.
- I worked mainly on developing frontends with React using Typescript for the frontend.

Jun 2021 – Jun 2022

Software Engineer

Xto10x

Bengaluru, Karnataka

• xto10x helps startups scale with their products such as 10x Goals, 10x People and 10x Performance which evaluates their eNPS and helps them scale from x to 10x.

Jan 2019 – May 2021

Software Engineer

Senseforth AI Research Pvt. Ltd.

Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Senseforth is a leading Conversational AI solutions Company provider that enables automated human-like conversations between organizations and people.
- Helped in developing and customizing client facing chatbots based on the requirements and needs.

• I worked mainly with React using Typescript for the frontend. Also very well versed with Unit testing with Jest and Enzyme.

June 2018 – November 2018 Software Developer Trainee CauseCode Technologies Pune, Maharashtra

- CauseCode is a mid-sized team with expertise in crafting mobile and web apps to help get promising startups on the map.
- I worked mainly with React and React Native using Typescript for the frontend with Graphql as a common interface between the client and the server. Also very well versed with Unit testing with Jest and Enzyme.

PROJECTS

- Content-SEO (May 2022 Present)
 - Worked on various tools and aspects of seo in a content such as , seo analytics, seo ranking, keyword portfolios. A user can enter a keyword topic or description for its content, and the tool helped them with improving their seo by giving suggestions regarding various aspects for that keyword.
- BLITZ (May 2021 Mar 2022)
 - Worked extensively on the in-house product as a front-end dev. Work involves requirements analysis, data modeling, technology exploration and selection, software design, construction, testing, and release. I worked mainly on developing micro-frontends with React using Typescript for the frontend.
- A.Ware (Jan 2019 May 2021)
 - I worked on the inhouse product A.ware, The Revolutionary AI Chatbot Platform with deep domain knowledge to build Intelligent Chatbots for Business. With A.ware's chat bot, a consumer can break away from the confines of manual work and experience the latest technological driven product that works like a personal assistant. tech stacks involved in building this product were react with typescript, redux, jquery and latest trend of html and css

EDUCATION

Bachelor, Technology

The LNM institute of Information & Technology Computer and Communication Engineering Jaipur, Rajasthan

Graduated, May 2018 CGPA 6.13

HOBBIES

- Worked for Aashman foundations, a non-profit organization as a volunteer to raise awareness and help in donations and funding for the community
- When not firefighting at work, I love a cup of Ginger Tea on a rainy evening, anything that involves jumping off from ridiculous heights (think airplanes and cliffs) or playing some tunes on my keyboard.